TRỊNH HOÀNG LONG

CONTACT ME

ABOUT ME

A passionate software developer who loves to learn and try out everything. Having dedicated over four years of my career to learning the intricacies of software development, and have since gained over two years of professional experience in the field, I do believe that my experiences as well as my qualifications will add value to your company as I have been instrumental in the success of some important projects in my position.

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

IELTS band 6.5 Academic, British Council, 2023

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Proficiency in database systems such as MySQL,PostGresQL, MongoDB, etc.
- Familiarity with version control systems such as Git or SVN.
- Experience with containerization technologies such as Docker.
- Good communication, often present the team's work to the crowd
- Knowledge of software development methodologies such as Agile or Scrum.

EXPERIENCES

Software Developer, App Engineering

Hitachi Vantara

3/2022-6/2023

- POD: Print Simulator
 - Developed and maintained a web-based print system.
 - Optimized the database schema and query performance of an existing function.

- Build a tool to migrate databases from MySQL to PostGresSQL.
- o Technology used: Java Spring Boot and Angular 8, Batch Script, PostGresSQL.
- Roles: Fullstack developer.
- EQO: EQUIOS Online
 - Developed and maintained a web-based to connect customers, designers and printing companies.
 - Handling features that required difficult logic and mathematics equations.
 - Roles: Fullstack developer.
 - Technology used: AngularJS, VB.NET, Microsoft SQL.

Software Developer, Intern

NhatTin Logistic

12/2022- 2/2022

- DiDongViet
 - Create API endpoint following REST API design.
 - Collaborated with a DiDongViet 's developers team to develop an ecommerce website.
 - Roles: Backend developer.
 - Technology used: NestJs, MySQL

Software Developer, Intern

Codelynx

10/2021-12/2022

- "Job Stack"
 - Learning to recreate a Restful API for the admin page of "Job Stack"
 - Learning all the fundamentals to become a web developer.
 - Working in English speaking environment
 - o Technology used: Clojure, Neo4j, GraphQL, ReactJs, Docker

Software Developer, Intern

GameLoft Viêt Nam

6/2021-8/2021

SAI Leap 2021 intern program

- Torchase:
 - Learn and create a 2D game using Cocos2dx framework and C++.
 - Learning all the fundamentals such as OOP, design patterns
 - Get a chance to talk and work with a foreign game designer.
 - Team's game won 1st prize in the final presentation.

Web Builder: Easy Mall 12/2021-8/2022

- Websites that help end-users to create an ecommerce website.
- Feature: Custom domain, Custom email, Drag and drop to build a website. Manage Products, Collections, Orders, Navigation.etc.. to build a complete ecommerce website.
- Roles and responsibilities:
 - Focused primarily on the development and maintenance of the editor module which is a
 web-based application to help end-users customize their website using drag and drop
 feature. This involved collaborating with team members to implement new features,
 optimize performance, and ensure the module was fully integrated with the rest of the
 system. Additionally, I was responsible for troubleshooting and resolving any issues
 related to the editor module.
 - In addition to my responsibilities with the editor module, I provided support for the backend of the software system, including configuring custom domains and developing APIs for website storage and display. This involved working closely with the backend development team to ensure seamless integration and optimal performance of the system.
 - In addition to my work on the editor module, I provided support for FrontEnd development, including recreating home pages, selling pages and customizing the 'react-sortable-tree' library to enable customized website navigation. I also help with the design of the application.
 - o Language and technologies: Reactjs, ExpressJS, Grapejs, PostGresSQL, Nodemailer.
 - Cloud platform: AWS RDS, AWS S3.
- Github frontend: https://github.com/nhaatjminh/easy-mall
- Github backend: https://github.com/trinhhoanglong2000/WebBuilder server
- Github editor: https://github.com/trinhhoanglong2000/WebBuilder_client
- Video Demo:

https://drive.google.com/file/d/14hdpBXs91zOh9t-XIFbnuQJRQW2KkQs6/view?usp=sharing

Moodle website

10/2021

- Websites that help teaching and learning come together.
- Roles:
 - FrontEnd: Create UI components using reactjs

- BackEnd: Create RestfulAPI using express
- Language and technologies: Reactis, ExpressJS, PostgresQL
- Github frontend: https://github.com/trinhhoanglong2000/BTN01 Group05 client
- Github backend: https://github.com/trinhhoanglong2000/BTN01 Group05 server

E-Commerce Website: Triple L

9/2020 - 11/2020

- Website allows users to search and buy clothing online.
- Role: responsible for the Front-end
- Language and technologies: VanillaJS, HTML, CSS, Express JS, PostgreSql, HandleBar
- Github: https://github.com/18127141/Web-Seller

EDUCATION

TP.HCM, Việt Nam

University of Science

2018-2022

- Bachelor's degree at Software Engineering
- GPA:3.09/4
- Average grade: 7.74/10

TP.HCM, Việt Nam

Big-O Coding

2020

- Certification Big-O Orange: Advanced Algorithms
- Certification Big-O Blue: Introduction to Algorithms

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND AWARDS

- Competed and won a gold medal in the Annual 30/4 Olympic contest.
- Participate in the Annual Tin Hoc Tre contest

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

Programing languages

C++, C, C#, Java, Go, SQL, Python, Javascript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Visual Basic

Technologies:

- AngularJS, Angular, ReactJS, VueJS, NestJS, VB.NET, Jquery, ExpressJS.
- GraphQL, Neo4j, Docker